Rice University Center for Civic Leadership records UA 367
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Center for Civic Leadership records
1990-2015
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 367
22.25 Linear Feet (25 boxes)
0.12 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0367aip_001 (0.12 GB)
0.018 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0367aip_002 (0.018 GB)
0.11 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0367aip_003 (0.11 GB)
0.008 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0367aip_004 (0.008 GB)
0.42 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0367aip_005 (0.42 GB)
1.7 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0367aip_006 (1.7 GB)
This collection consists of materials from the Center for Civic Leadership offices. It includes office files and journals and scrapbooks created by students.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials from the Center for Civic Leadership offices. It includes office files, journals and scrapbooks created by students, and photographs.
Historical Sketch
In 1995, the Community Involvement Center (CIC) and Leadership Rice emerged as two branches of Rice University's community outreach effort. The CIC focused on introducing students to the Houston community and the world beyond through community service with programs like the International Service Project and Alternative Spring Break. Leadership Rice promoted leadership skills and opportunities among Rice students.
In 2006, under the auspices of the Quality Enhancement Plan, CIC and Leadership Rice came under the umbrella of the newly created Center for Civic Engagement (CCE). In 2013, CCE became the Center for Civic Leadership (CCL). Its current mission is "foster engaged citizenship through integrated curricular and experiential learning opportunities, and to cultivate mutually beneficial university-community partnerships that promote positive, sustainable change in Houston, the United States, and around the world."
Sources used: https://ccl.rice.edu/about-us/
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials donated by Jacqueline Jones and Michael Domeracki in 2015.
Accruals
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Some materials in the addenda are restricted. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Social life and customs; College students -- Texas; Politics and government
- Series I: General, 1996-2014
  - Alternative Spring Break, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alternative Spring Break, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Alternative Spring Break, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Austin, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Boulder Creek, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Camp Campbell, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Camp Campbell, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Camp Campbell, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Denver, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Eagle Butte, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Hidalgo, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Honduras, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Houston, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Houston Interfaith, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Lafayette, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Mexico, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Reynosa, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Navajo Nation, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alternative Spring Break - New Jersey, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Alternative Spring Break - San Francisco, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Alternative Spring Break - Trip Reports, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Center for Civic Engagement packet, ca. 2005 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Center for Civic Engagement brochure, ca. 2013 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Circle of Giving, 2002-2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Good Works Fair, 1996-2007 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Leadership Certificate as a Second Major, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Leadership Rice, 1997-2000, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Leadership Rice - Living It, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Leadership Rice - Living It, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Leadership Rice - Living It, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Leadership Rice - Living It, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Leadership Rice - Living It, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Leadership Rice - Living It, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Leadership Rice - Living It, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Mentors, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Murray, Jennifer, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Rice Undergraduate Research Symposium, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Rice Undergraduate Research Symposium, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rice Undergraduate Research Symposium, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Service Council, 1996/1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Service Council, 2000/2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Service Council, 2001/2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Service Council, 2002/2003 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Service Council, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Service Council, 2004/2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Service Council, 2005/2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - UNIV 309 Teaching Assistants, ca. 2005 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Urban Immersion, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series II: Journals, 1992-2014
  - Journals, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Journals, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Journals, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Journals, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Journals, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Journals, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Journals, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
  - Journals, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 10-12)
  - Journals, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 13-15)
  - Journals, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Journals, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Journals, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 3-9)
  - Journals, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
  - Journals, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 1-7)
  - Journals, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 8-12)
  - Journals, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Journals, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 4-8)
  - Journals, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 9-12)
  - Journals, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- Series III: Negatives, Photographs, and Slides, 1990-2013
  - Photographs, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Slides, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Slides, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Slides, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Slides, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Slides, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 15-16)
  - Slides, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
  - Slides, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Negatives, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Photographs, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 22-23)
  - Slides, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Photographs, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Negatives, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Photographs and digital images, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    Scope and Contents
    "Guatemala images" consists of digital images (jpgs) from a trip to Guatemala.
  - Photographs, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Photographs, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Photographs, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
  - Photographs and digital images, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    "Reyonosa images" consists of digital images (jpgs) of a trip to Reynosa, Mexico.
  - Negatives, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Photographs and digital images, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    "Galveston images" consists of digital images (jpgs) of the Alternative Spring Break trip to Galveston.
  - Photographs, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, 2011 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Photographs, 2013 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Negatives, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
  - Slides, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Digital images, 2003-2012
- Series IV: Scrapbooks, 2003-2015
  - 2003 (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
  - 2005 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
  - 2006 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - 2008 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 2009 (Box 9, Folder 2-7)
  - 2010 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 2011 (Box 9, Folder 9-12)
  - 2011 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - 2012 (Box 10, Folder 3-7)
  - 2013 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - 2015 (Box 10, Folder 10-12)
  - n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
- Series V: Oversize Scrapbooks, 1993-2014
  - 1993 (3) (Box 12)
  - 2005 (1) (Box 12)
  - 2005 (1) (Box 13)
  - 2006 (1) (Box 13)
  - 2007 (1) (Box 13)
  - 2007 (2) (Box 14)
  - 2008 (1) (Box 14)
  - 2008 (1) (Box 15)
  - 2009 (2) (Box 15)
  - 2010 (3) (Box 16)
  - 2010 (2) (Box 17)
  - 2010 (1) (Box 18)
  - 2011 (2) (Box 18)
  - 2011 (1) (Box 19)
  - 2012 (2) (Box 19)
  - 2012 (2) (Box 20)
  - 2013 (2) (Box 20)
  - 2013 (3) (Box 21)
  - 2013 (2) (Box 22)
  - 2013 (1) (Box 23)
  - 2014 (1) (Box 23)
- Series VI: Memorabilia
  - Leadership Rice pencils (2), 2000s (Box 23)
- Series VII: Video
  - Alternative Spring Break-Guatemala Videos, San Lucas (VHS), n.d. (Box 24)
  - Rice RSVP 9:25 (VHS), n.d. (Box 24)
  - Outreach Day (VHS), 1994 (Box 24)
  - Outreach Day (Video Cassette), 1987 (Box 24)
- Series VIII: Addenda, 1998-2003
  - Correspondence, 1998-2002 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - In-Class Evaluations, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Mentorship Program, 1999-2002 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Estimated Budget, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - General, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 7)